newsflare.com 2019-07-02

# Newsflare

This Newsflare website ("Website") is operated by Newsflare Limited whose registered address is: 

Newsflare Limited   
Scriptor Court   
157 Farringdon Road   
London, EC1R 3AD   
United Kingdom 

The terms "Newsflare", "we", "us", "our" and "ours" when used in this Privacy Policy mean Newsflare Ltd which includes all entities under the control of Newsflare Ltd. 

The terms "you", "your" and "yours" when used in this Privacy Policy mean any user of this Website. 

### Introduction to Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy describes our current policies and practices on personal data collected by us from you directly and/or through the Website. The term "personal data" refers to personally identifiable information about you; this can include your name, birthday, e-mail address, certain location data or mailing address, job description, and health-related data.

Please note that by submitting personal data manually or in electronic form to us and/or by using our Website you give your consent that all personal data on each occasion that you submit may be processed by Newsflare, in the manner and for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy.

You may be accessing our Website from a computer or mobile phone device (through an iPhone application, for example) and this policy govern your use of our Website regardless of the means of access. We also like to interact with you on third party sites where we post content or invite your feedback, such as www.facebook.com/newsflare and www.twitter.com/newsflare ("Third Party Sites").

Please note, this website is not intended for children and we do not knowingly collect data relating to children.

### Notification of changes to this Privacy Policy

We are continually improving our means and channels of communication, and adding new functionality and features to this website and to our existing services. Because of these ongoing changes, changes in the law and the changing nature of technology, our data practices will change from time to time. If and when our data practices change, we will notify you of the changes via this page. We encourage you to check this Privacy Policy frequently.

### Collection of personal data

You may provide us with your personal data so that you can receive information, advice, or services from us. We collect the following kinds of data:

Identity Data (to set up your account) includes username, email address and password to set up your account. There is the option to add your telephone number and physical address once you have set up your account. We use this.

Profile Data (optional on your account) includes company of employment, occupation, equipment, biography and interests.

Financial Data includes Paypal email address and may include bank account or payment card details.

Technical Data includes internet protocol (IP) address, your login data, browser type and version, time zone setting and location, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform and other technology on the devices you use to access this website.

Usage Data includes information about how you use our website, products and services which may be gathered via cookies on our website.

Communications Data includes your preferences in receiving communications from us and your communication preferences.

If you register with us, as part of the registration process, you will share some personal information, such as your name and e-mail address. You do not have to be a registered user to visit the Website. But, you do have to register if you want to upload videos, associated data interact with the Website or make full use of our services. Once you register, you will have an account with Newsflare and a password to access that account. You may never use another person's account without permission, and you may not use anyone else's password. Where we need to collect personal data by law, or under the terms of a contract we have with you and you fail to provide that data when requested, we may not be able to perform the contract we have or are trying to enter into with you (for example, to provide you with goods or services). In this case, we may have to cancel a product or service you have with us but we will notify you if this is the case at the time.

You should keep your registration details and all other information provided to us current and complete. You are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of your account and password. Please also let us know immediately if there is any unauthorized use of your account or password. We recommend that you always log out from your account at the end of a session with us to prevent other people from accessing your account without your permission. You represent and warrant that all the information you provide in your public profile and user account is accurate and complete. You are solely responsible for any activity occurring on your user account.

We sometimes supplement the information that you provide with information that is received from third parties. For instance, if inaccurate post codes are received, we may verify your location using your IP address.

We also reserve the right to monitor and/or record your communication with us by mail, voice, email or any other form of transmission for the purposes of quality control, security and other business needs. Any personal data contained in such recorded information will be processed in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy.

We may also receive your personal data from other members of Newsflare, our service providers, agents, advisers or business partners, including, without limitation, news agencies. Where personal data is disclosed to us by third parties, it is the obligation of the disclosing party to ensure such personal data is disclosed with requisite authority and consent, and we will process such personal data in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

### Your public profile

Once you become a registered user with is, you may provide additional information to your Newsflare profile describing your skills, experiences, background and other information. Providing additional information about you, beyond what is minimally required at registration, is entirely up to you. Any information you provide at registration or in your profile section may be used by us as described our Terms of Service and this Privacy Policy. You can review the personal information you have provided to us and make any desired changes to the information that you publish, or to the settings for your account, including your email and contact preferences, at any time by logging in to your account on the Website. Please be aware that even after your request for a change is processed, we may, for a reasonable time, retain residual information about you in the backup and/or archival copies of our database.

### Use of personal data

We process your personal data, and share your personal data with others, only for specific and limited purposes when the law allows. We ask only for data that is adequate, relevant and not excessive for those purposes. Some of these purposes may include the following:

  * For the purposes of managing your account and content that you upload or licence from the site
  * To process your request for information or advice
  * To help diagnose any problems with our server and administer our website
  * Where we need to perform the contract we are about to enter into or have entered into with you, including when we mainly need contact you to help editorialise a story better
  * To verify information and content that you have provided to us
  * Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests
  * Where we need to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation
  * To process your payments, which may include your postal and e-mail addresses. We may also receive the billing and payment information that you provide when your purchase is processed by another party, such as Paypal. Our Terms of Service explain our policies and terms relevant to our charges and billing practices
  * You will receive marketing communications from us if you provided us with your details when you registered for that mailing list and, in each case when you have opted in to receiving that marketing

We will only use your personal data for the purposes for which we collected it, unless we reasonably consider that we need to use it for another reason and that reason is compatible with the original purpose. If you wish to get an explanation as to how the processing for the new purpose is compatible with the original purpose, please contact us.

If we need to use your personal data for an unrelated purpose, we will notify you and we will explain the legal basis, which allows us to do so.

Please note that we may process your personal data without your knowledge or consent, in compliance with the above rules, where this is required or permitted by law.

### Data Retention

We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.

To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.

Upon expiry of the applicable retention period we will securely destroy your personal data in accordance with applicable laws and regulations. In some circumstances we may anonymise your personal data so that it can no longer be associated with you, in which case it is no longer personal data.

### Publicly Accessible Information

We offer you the opportunity to post, submit and exchange content and information on publicly accessible areas of our Website. You should exercise caution if you choose to disclose personally identifiable information in a publicly accessible area. Remember that this information may remain indefinitely in the publicly accessible area of the website. Also, other users may also be able to view two or more of your individual postings collectively. You are solely responsible for any information that you disclose and disseminate on publicly accessible areas. If you have a concern about any personally identifiable information you have posted on any publicly accessible areas and are unable to delete or edit it, please contact us.

### Anonymous data collected through this website

In addition to the information we collect as described above, we use technology to collect anonymous information about the use of our website. For example, we use technology to track which pages of our website our visitors view. We also use technology to determine which Web browsers our visitors use. This technology does not identify you personally; it simply enables us to compile statistics about our visitors and their use of our website.

We use this anonymous data to improve the content and functionality of our Website and our e-mail updates, to better understand our customers and visitors, and to improve the services we offer.

### Cookies

To collect the anonymous data described in the preceding paragraph, we may use temporary "cookies" that remain in the cookies file of your browser until the browser is closed. Cookies by themselves cannot be used to discover the identity of the user. A cookie is a small piece of information which is sent to your browser and stored on your computer's hard drive. Cookies do not damage your computer. You can set your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie. This enables you to decide if you want to accept it or not. We also use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer our website. An IP address is a numeric code that identifies your computer on a network, or in this case, the Internet. Your IP address is also used to gather broad demographic information, such as determining how many of our visitors are from outside of the UK. We may also perform IP lookups to determine which domain you are coming from (i.e: aol.com, yourcompany.com) to assess our users' demographics more accurately.

### Disclosure of your personal data

We do not share with, nor sell, nor distribute your personal data to unrelated third parties, except under these limited circumstances:

  * personal data may occasionally be transferred to third parties who act for us for further processing in accordance with the purposes for which the data was originally collected, or for purposes to which you have consented or otherwise in accordance with this Privacy Policy. For example, sometimes a third party may have access to your personal data in order to support our information technology or to handle mailings on our behalf.
  * We will provide your information to third party companies to perform services on our behalf, including payment processing, data analysis, e-mail delivery, hosting services and customer service, namely: 
    * Zencoder - cloud-based transcoding service
    * Xero - cloud-based accounting software
    * PayPal - global payment engine
    * Mailchimp - email management
    * Mandrill - email management
    * Act-on – marketing automation
    * HubSpot - marketing automation
    * Zendesk -  Customer service software
    * HubSpot -  Customer-relationship management
    * Keen.io - Analytics for user-based events
    * Filestack - File upload service
    * Jwplayer - Web-based video player
    * Matillion \- ETL software
    * Snowflake - Data warehouse
    * Tableau - Interactive data visualisation and business intelligence software
    * Google Analytics - Web analytics service
    * Pipedrive - Cloud-based sales software
  * We direct all such third party service providers to maintain the confidentiality of the information disclosed to them and not to use your information for any purpose other than to provide services on our behalf. Please note that payments made by third party payment providers may also be subject to additional policies.
  * Unless you have given us your consent to the processing of your personal data in accordance with our Privacy Policy (which includes sharing or other disclosing), we will not share or disclose your personal data to any unrelated third parties for their own marketing purposes.
  * We may share or transfer the information in our databases to comply with a legal or regulatory requirement, for the administration of justice, interacting with anti-fraud databases, to protect your vital interests, to protect the security or integrity of our databases or this website, to take precautions against legal liability, or in the event of our sale, merger, reorganisation, transfer of business, dissolution or similar event.
  * If we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we may disclose your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets, but only once such transaction has gone through.

Where appropriate, before disclosing personal data to a third party, we require the third party, contractually, to take adequate precautions to protect that data and to comply with applicable law.

### Data Integrity and Security

We strive to maintain the reliability, accuracy, completeness and currency of personal data in our databases and to protect the privacy and security of our databases. The security measures in place on our website and computer systems, aim to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of the information you provide to us. We keep your personal data only for as long as reasonably necessary for the purposes for which it was collected or to comply with any applicable legal or regulatory requirements, or our data retention policy.

We urge you to protect your own privacy. We recommend that you do not share your password with anyone or share your password in an unsolicited phone call or e-mail.

Unfortunately, despite all of our efforts, there is always a risk that third parties may unlawfully intercept transmissions. For example, we cannot ensure the security of your data during transmission to us or the security of your data on an iPhone, Android (or other telephone device that can use phone applications) or on another computer. This reality is true of all Internet or data transmission use. As a result, we cannot ensure the security of any information you transmit, and you transmit all information at your own risk. We have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so.

### Location-Based Services

When you upload videos, data and/or images ("Content") using the Newsflare App on a device, we collect location information. We collect two forms of location data, in both instances pertaining to the Content you submit: (i) GPS Geographic Location Data from the App installed on your device(ii) Image File Data: we collect EXIF file metadata, this metadata is usually automatically tagged to your Content. We collect and use both of these two sources of location information to verify the geo-location of the Content you submit, we also pass this information to our third party media buyers for the same purpose. We obtain your consent to collect this data on the registration page of our website, and on the first instance you use the Newsflare App on your device.

### Inaccurate Data

We encourage you to ensure that your personal data is accurate and kept up to date, so please regularly update any information you have given to us by sending an email to privacy@newsflare.com, or by writing to us.

### Links to other websites

Our Website may contain hyperlinks to websites that are not operated by us. Any such hyperlinks are provided for your reference and convenience only and do not imply any endorsement of the activities of these third-party websites or any association with their operators. We do not control these websites and are not responsible for their data or privacy practices. We urge you to review any privacy policy posted on any site you visit before using the site or providing any personal data about yourself.

Our Website contains hyperlinks to other pages on our Website. We may use technology to track how often these links are used and which pages on our Website our visitors choose to view. Again this technology does not identify you personally - it simply enables us to compile statistics about the use of these hyperlinks.

### Transfer of Data Abroad

We may transfer data between Newsflare's offices and third party processors, which may be located outside the EEA. Where your personal data is transferred outside the EEA we will ensure that the recipient agrees to keep your information confidential and hold it securely in accordance with the requirements of applicable data legislation.

If you are visiting our website from a country other than the country in which our servers are located, the various communications will necessarily result in the transfer of information across international boundaries.

By providing us with your personal data, you consent to the processing and transfer of your data as set out in this section.

### Your Data Rights

We want you to remain in control of your personal information. Part of this is making sure you understand your legal rights, which are as follows:

  1. where your personal information is processed on the basis of consent, the right to withdraw that consent;
  2. the right to confirmation as to whether or not we are holding any of your personal information and, if we are, to obtain a copy of it;
  3. from 25 May 2018, the right to have certain data provided to you in a portable electronic format (where technically feasible);
  4. the right to have inaccurate personal information rectified;
  5. the right to object to your personal information being used for marketing or profiling, or on the basis of our or a third party's legitimate interests;
  6. the right to restrict how your personal information is used; and
  7. the right to be forgotten, which allows you to have your personal information erased in certain circumstances (though this is not an absolute right and may not apply if we need to continue using it for a lawful reason).

Please keep in mind that there are exceptions to the rights above and, though we will always try to respond to your satisfaction, there may be situations where we are unable to do so (for example, because the information no longer exists or there is an exception which applies to your request).

If you are not happy with our response, or you believe that your data protection or privacy rights have been infringed, you should contact the UK Information Commissioner's Office, which oversees data protection compliance in the UK. Details of how to do this can be found at [www.ico.org.uk](https://www.ico.org.uk/).

### Unsubscribe

We hope you will be delighted with our services. If you no longer wish to receive information from us and want to be removed from our standard mailing list you can "unsubscribe" by email or post by contacting us at the address given below. We will remove you from mailing lists as soon as practicable but please allow up to thirty days for the unsubscribe process to be completed.

Remember that by stopping the information that you receive from us about our products and services may not benefit you.

If you do not want to receive unsolicited mail from any source, you can stop this by registering with the "Mailing Preference Service". There are also telephone, fax and email preference services. For more information on the preference services, please visit the Direct Marketing Association's website.

### Governing Law

This Privacy Policy forms part of our website Terms of Business and as such shall be governed by and construed in accordance with the laws of England and Wales. You agree to submit any dispute arising out of your use of this website to the exclusive jurisdiction of the courts of England.

### Contact Details and Data Access

We have appointed a data privacy manager who is responsible for overseeing questions in relation to this privacy notice. If you have any questions about this privacy notice, including any requests to exercise your rights, please contact the data privacy manager using the details set out below: Our postal address is:

Newsflare Limited   
Scriptor Court   
157 Farringdon Road   
London EC1R 3AD   
United Kingdom 

You have the right to make a complaint at any time to the Information Commissioner's Office (ICO), the UK supervisory authority for data protection issues (www.ico.org.uk). We would, however, appreciate the chance to deal with your concerns before you approach the ICO so please contact us in the first instance.

No fee usually required   
You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive. Alternatively, we may refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances.

What we may need from you   
We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response.

Time limit to respond   
We try to respond to all legitimate requests within one month. Occasionally it may take us longer than a month if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated.

Privacy Policy last updated May 2018.
